The story of a boy suddenly alone in the world. The men who
challenge him. And the girl who helps him become a man.
The Man from Snowy River is a drama, romance,
adventure film directed by George T. Miller.
Jim Craig has lived his first 18 years in the
mountains of Australia on his father's farm.
The death of his father forces him to go to the lowlands to earn
enough money to get the farm back on its feet.
Jim Craig, played by Tom Burlinson.
Jessica Harrison, played by Sigrid Thornton.
Henry Craig, played by Terence Donovan.
Harrison / Spur, played by Kirk Douglas.
Clancy, played by Jack Thompson.
Mountain Man, played by Tommy Dysart.
The Man from Snowy River is a 1982 Australian Western drama film based on the Banjo Paterson poem "The Man from Snowy River." The film stars Kirk Douglas in dual roles as the brothers Harrison (a character who appeared
frequently in Paterson's poems) and Spur, Jack Thompson as Clancy, Tom Burlinson as Jim Craig, Sigrid Thornton as Harrison's daughter Jessica, Terence Donovan as Jim's father, Henry Craig, and Chris Haywood as Curly.
Both Burlinson and Thornton later reprised their roles in the 1988 sequel, The Man
from Snowy River II, which was distributed by Walt Disney Pictures.
The film explores themes of australia, regret, horseback riding, river, horse.
The tone is emotional.